<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>About on Daniel Furman</title><link>https://daniel-furman.github.io/</link><description>Recent content in About on Daniel Furman</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://daniel-furman.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Field experiment on dating attitudes towards academic prestige</title><link>https://daniel-furman.github.io/posts/tinder_field_experiment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://daniel-furman.github.io/posts/tinder_field_experiment/</guid><description>Field experiment on dating attitudes towards academic prestige in The Bay Area By Daniel Furman, Forrest Brandt, and Jackie Hu
Berkeley Spring 2022, Causual Inference with Prof. Josue Martinez Objective How significant is one’s academic prestige for online dating in the Bay Area? Are dating attitudes towards academic achievements different between men and women in the Bay Area?
The widespread adoption of online dating apps enables social scientists to perform field experiments probing the underlying psychology of human dating, for example, how social attractiveness influences dating dynamics.</description></item><item><title>Extracting metadata from social media captions with machine learning.</title><link>https://daniel-furman.github.io/posts/social-media-profiling-blog/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://daniel-furman.github.io/posts/social-media-profiling-blog/</guid><description>A blog post &amp;amp; Web-App exploring social media profiling with machine learning. Web-app on Heroku: https://social-media-profiler.herokuapp.com (models are de-activated due to prohibitive GCP Natural Language AutoML costs).
Overview: This design doc’s purpose is to provide a write-up for the corresponding web-application above. Profiling metadata is valuable for a range of purposes, such as for creating better personalized advertisements online. However, this is clearly a sensitive topic, because people have a range of both positive and negative opinions about internet privacy.</description></item><item><title>Visualizing 40,000+ celebrity Tweets, IG captions &amp; FB posts with RShiny.</title><link>https://daniel-furman.github.io/posts/social-media-nlp-viz/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://daniel-furman.github.io/posts/social-media-nlp-viz/</guid><description>A highly scientific visualization of 40k+ celebrity Twitter, Instagram &amp;amp; Facebook posts. As featured on shinyapps: https://dryanfurman.shinyapps.io/celeb-social-media-captions/</description></item><item><title>Forecasting Surf Crowds in Malibu with a Web-App UI.</title><link>https://daniel-furman.github.io/posts/surfcrowdsai/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://daniel-furman.github.io/posts/surfcrowdsai/</guid><description>Forecasting Surf Crowds in Malibu with a Web-App UI As featured on Heroku: SurfCrowds.ai.</description></item><item><title>Style Clustering for Instagram BFY-Food Influencers with NLP.</title><link>https://daniel-furman.github.io/posts/bfy-food-insta-clustering/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://daniel-furman.github.io/posts/bfy-food-insta-clustering/</guid><description>Style Clustering for Instagram BFY-Food Influencers with NLP As featured on shinyapps: https://dryanfurman.shinyapps.io/caption_clustering/</description></item><item><title>DAT/Artathon EcoRisk Forecasts - California DataViz.</title><link>https://daniel-furman.github.io/posts/datartathon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://daniel-furman.github.io/posts/datartathon/</guid><description>DAT/Artathon EcoRisk Forecasts - California DataViz As featured in D/A&amp;rsquo;s gallery: https://datartathon.com/projects/2021-daniel-ecorisk-california
Made with the support of the Risk &amp;amp; Resilience DAT/Artathon 2021.
“EcoRisk California” explores climate change impacts for three of the West Coast’s most beloved tree species during the 21st century. The motion-graphics storyboard visualizes shifts within three species distributions across spatial and climate dimensions, exploring relationships between ecological risk and habitat suitability. To facilitate future experiments, the study is accompanied by an open-sourced Python package containing the class for semi-automated machine learning used in the visualization.</description></item><item><title>BirdCLEF21 Kaggle Competition Write Up.</title><link>https://daniel-furman.github.io/posts/birdclef21-kaggle-competition-write-up/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://daniel-furman.github.io/posts/birdclef21-kaggle-competition-write-up/</guid><description>BirdCLEF21 Kaggle Competition Write Up. [Code] Bird song recognition with AI has the potential to streamline (by semi-automating) scientific monitoring of bird assemblages. Faster identification of bird species in natural settings, as a result, equips land managers and policy-makers with a stronger understanding of environmental risks in ecological systems.
The BirdCLEF21 Kaggle challenge brought state of the art in computer vision to bird song recognition, tasking competitors to classify species from bird calls into 397 target classes.</description></item><item><title>Using Numerical Mathematics to Approximate the Golden Ratio.</title><link>https://daniel-furman.github.io/posts/numerical-math-mondays-approximating-the-golden-ratio/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://daniel-furman.github.io/posts/numerical-math-mondays-approximating-the-golden-ratio/</guid><description>Using Numerical Mathematics to Approximate the Golden Ratio Introduction and historical context I will approximate the golden ratio by iteratively taking ratios of consecutive terms in the Fibonacci sequence. This algorithm lets us peer into the underlying relationship between the Fibonacci sequence and the golden ratio, illuminating a number of interesting patterns.
The golden ratio is a mathematical phenomenon between two numbers, say, a and b. Let a &amp;gt; b, if the ratio of $$\frac{a}{b}$$ is the same as $$\frac{(a+b)}{a}$$, then the ratio is ~$$\frac{1.</description></item><item><title>Solving a Partnership Restructuring Problem with a Markov Model.</title><link>https://daniel-furman.github.io/posts/solving-a-partnership-restructuring-problem-with-computational-linear-algerba/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 21:22:42 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://daniel-furman.github.io/posts/solving-a-partnership-restructuring-problem-with-computational-linear-algerba/</guid><description>Solving a Partnership Restructuring Problem with a Markov Model. Intro Consider a partnership restructuring its assets into majority ownerships among N partners, who previously shared M assets unevenly (debt + value). The asset structure directly reflects the partners&amp;rsquo; differing ownership stakes in the business. Here, I aimed to re-distribute the assets into majority ownerships without altering the partnership stakes, minimizing potential restructuring taxes levied if the asset ownerships changed significantly between partners.</description></item><item><title>Bookshelf</title><link>https://daniel-furman.github.io/bookshelf/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://daniel-furman.github.io/bookshelf/</guid><description>Favorite Reads Book Author Finished Quotes Becoming Wild: How Animal Cultures Raise Families, Create Beauty, and Achieve Peace Carl Safina 2022 &amp;ldquo;The philosopher Immanuel Kant asserted, &amp;ldquo;Man is the only being who needs education.&amp;rdquo; But if he&amp;rsquo;d said, &amp;ldquo;not the only being,&amp;rdquo; he&amp;rsquo;d have been correct.&amp;rdquo; Storytelling with Data: A Data Visualization Guide for Business Professionals Cole Nussbaumer Knafic 2021 &amp;ldquo;Exploratory analysis is what you do to understand the data and figure out what might be noteworthy or interesting to highlight to others.</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://daniel-furman.github.io/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://daniel-furman.github.io/contact/</guid><description>Contact dryanfurman (at) gmail
Links LinkedIn Google Scholar Github PyPi Kaggle</description></item><item><title>Resume</title><link>https://daniel-furman.github.io/resume/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://daniel-furman.github.io/resume/</guid><description>Resume Contact me for my Resume, dryanfurman (at) gmail.</description></item></channel></rss>