<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>About on Daniel Furman</title><link>https://daniel-furman.github.io/</link><description>Recent content in About on Daniel Furman</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://daniel-furman.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Using Data-Driven Insights to Improve the Official World Golf Rankings.</title><link>https://daniel-furman.github.io/posts/owgr/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://daniel-furman.github.io/posts/owgr/</guid><description>Using Data-Driven Insights to Improve the Official World Golf Rankings Does the Official World Golf Rankings Ltd. (OWGR) fairly rank professional golfers? I approached this question through data mining and unsupervised learning methods with over two decades worth of OWGR proprietary data. Ultimately, the OWGR decided to ship ranking system updates at scale in Q3 2022 that more accurately reflect true athletic performance in professional golf tournaments worldwide.
My background in competitive golf was well-suited to this problem domain, helping me think about ways to extend the research questions beyond the three stake-holder prescribed objectives.</description></item><item><title>DAT/Artathon EcoRisk Forecasts - California DataViz.</title><link>https://daniel-furman.github.io/posts/datartathon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://daniel-furman.github.io/posts/datartathon/</guid><description>DAT/Artathon EcoRisk Forecasts - California DataViz As featured in D/A's gallery: https://datartathon.com/projects/2021-daniel-ecorisk-california
Made with the support of the Risk &amp;amp; Resilience DAT/Artathon 2021.
“EcoRisk California” visualizes climate change impacts for three of the West Coast’s most beloved tree species during the 21st century. The motion-graphics storyboard visualizes shifts within three species distributions across spatial and climate dimensions, exploring relationships between ecological risk and habitat suitability. To facilitate future experiments, the study is accompanied by an open-sourced Python package containing the class for semi-automated machine learning used in the visualization.</description></item><item><title>BirdCLEF21 Kaggle Competition Write Up.</title><link>https://daniel-furman.github.io/posts/birdclef21-kaggle-competition-write-up/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://daniel-furman.github.io/posts/birdclef21-kaggle-competition-write-up/</guid><description>BirdCLEF21 Kaggle Competition Write Up. [Code] Bird song recognition with AI has the potential to streamline (by semi-automating) scientific monitoring of bird assemblages. Faster identification of bird species in natural settings, as a result, equips land managers and policy-makers with a stronger understanding of environmental risks in ecological systems. The BirdCLEF21 Kaggle challenge brought state of the art in computer vision to bird song recognition, tasking competitors to classify species from bird calls into 397 target classes.</description></item><item><title>Numerical Math Mondays: Approximating the golden ratio.</title><link>https://daniel-furman.github.io/posts/numerical-math-mondays-approximating-the-golden-ratio/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://daniel-furman.github.io/posts/numerical-math-mondays-approximating-the-golden-ratio/</guid><description>Numerical Math Mondays: Approximating the golden ratio.
Introduction and historical context I am going to approximate the golden ratio with numerical methods, by iteratively taking ratios of consecutive terms in the Fibonacci sequence. This algorithm lets us peer into the underlying relationship between the Fibonacci sequence and the golden ratio, helping us understand many interesting mathematical applications. For more reading on applications, see the Appendix.
For a little background: What is the golden ratio anyways?</description></item><item><title>Solving a partnership restructuring problem with Markov processes.</title><link>https://daniel-furman.github.io/posts/solving-a-partnership-restructuring-problem-with-computational-linear-algerba/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 21:22:42 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://daniel-furman.github.io/posts/solving-a-partnership-restructuring-problem-with-computational-linear-algerba/</guid><description>Solving a partnership restructuring problem with Markov processes. Consider a partnership restructuring its assets. The N partners currently share each of the M assets at a given percentage. Our task is to re-distribute the assets such that each is under majority ownership. Critically, we need to divvy the assets without altering the overall value and debt associated with each partner. In effect, we want to split up the assets fairly.</description></item><item><title>Bookshelf</title><link>https://daniel-furman.github.io/bookshelf/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://daniel-furman.github.io/bookshelf/</guid><description>Favorite Reads Book Author Finished Quotes Data Science in Production: Building Scalable Model Pipelines with Python Ben Weber 2021 &amp;ldquo;Putting predictive models into production is one of the most direct ways that data scientists can add value to an organization.&amp;rdquo; Range: Why Generalists Triumph in a Specialized World David Epstein 2021 &amp;ldquo;Seeing small pieces of a larger jigsaw puzzle in isolation, no matter how hi-def the picture, is insufficient to grapple with humanity&amp;rsquo;s greatest challenges.</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://daniel-furman.github.io/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://daniel-furman.github.io/contact/</guid><description>Contact dryanfurman (at) gmail
Social Profiles LinkedIn Github PyPi Kaggle Resume Resume available upon request.</description></item><item><title>Resume</title><link>https://daniel-furman.github.io/resume/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://daniel-furman.github.io/resume/</guid><description>Resume available upon request.</description></item></channel></rss>