<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>About on Daniel Furman</title><link>https://daniel-furman.github.io/</link><description>Recent content in About on Daniel Furman</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://daniel-furman.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>DAT/Artathon EcoRisk Forecasts - California DataViz.</title><link>https://daniel-furman.github.io/posts/datartathon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://daniel-furman.github.io/posts/datartathon/</guid><description>A data-driven story about California's uncertain climate future, indicating worrisome levels of temperature warming and precipitation decline, particularly in the Sierra Nevadas (Giant sequoias) and Mojave Desert (Joshua trees) respectively. These climatic trends unfortunately have the potential to intensify wildfire, drought, and biodiversity decline across the West Coast.
Made with the support of the Risk &amp;amp; Resilience DAT/Artathon 2021.
Code:
Git Repo Sources:
NYT CA Fires
IPCC AR6 Report WorldClim2.</description></item><item><title>BirdCLEF21 Kaggle Competition Write Up.</title><link>https://daniel-furman.github.io/posts/birdclef21-kaggle-competition-write-up/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://daniel-furman.github.io/posts/birdclef21-kaggle-competition-write-up/</guid><description>BirdCLEF21 Kaggle Competition Write Up. [Code] Bird song recognition with AI has the potential to streamline (by semi-automating) scientific monitoring of bird assemblages. Faster identification of bird species in natural settings, as a result, equips land managers and policy-makers with a stronger understanding of environmental risks in ecological systems. The BirdCLEF21 Kaggle challenge brought state of the art in computer vision to bird song recognition, tasking competitors to classify species from bird calls into 397 target classes.</description></item><item><title>Numerical Math Mondays: Approximating the golden ratio.</title><link>https://daniel-furman.github.io/posts/numerical-math-mondays-approximating-the-golden-ratio/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://daniel-furman.github.io/posts/numerical-math-mondays-approximating-the-golden-ratio/</guid><description>Numerical Math Mondays: Approximating the golden ratio.
Introduction and historical context I am going to approximate the golden ratio with numerical methods, by iteratively taking ratios of consecutive terms in the Fibonacci sequence. This algorithm lets us peer into the underlying relationship between the Fibonacci sequence and the golden ratio, helping us understand many interesting mathematical applications. For more reading on applications, see the Appendix.
For a little background: What is the golden ratio anyways?</description></item><item><title>Solving a partnership restructuring problem with Markov processes.</title><link>https://daniel-furman.github.io/posts/solving-a-partnership-restructuring-problem-with-computational-linear-algerba/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 21:22:42 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://daniel-furman.github.io/posts/solving-a-partnership-restructuring-problem-with-computational-linear-algerba/</guid><description>Solving a partnership restructuring problem with Markov processes. Consider a partnership restructuring its assets. The N partners currently share each of the M assets at a given percentage. Our task is to re-distribute the assets such that each is under majority ownership. Critically, we need to divvy the assets without altering the overall value and debt associated with each partner. In effect, we want to split up the assets fairly.</description></item><item><title>Bookshelf</title><link>https://daniel-furman.github.io/bookshelf/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://daniel-furman.github.io/bookshelf/</guid><description>Favorite Reads Book Author Finished Quotes Range: Why Generalists Triumph in a Specialized World David Epstein 2021 &amp;ldquo;Seeing small pieces of a larger jigsaw puzzle in isolation, no matter how hi-def the picture, is insufficient to grapple with humanity&amp;rsquo;s greatest challenges.&amp;rdquo; Superforecasting: The Art and Science of Prediction Philip E. Tetlock and Dan Gardner 2021 &amp;ldquo;For scientists, not knowing is exciting. It’s an opportunity to discover; the more that is unknown, the greater the opportunity.</description></item><item><title>Coding</title><link>https://daniel-furman.github.io/coding/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://daniel-furman.github.io/coding/</guid><description>Code Links Description lwMCMC A parameter space sampling class for lightweight Bayesian inference. Running on a NumPy-based implementation of the Metropolis-Hastings algorithm. PySDMs An object-oriented Python class for semi-auto ML geo-classification (running on PyCaret). Compares gradient boosted tree algorithms by default, with options to include soft voters and NNs. Designed for Species Distribution Modeling applications. RecFeatureSelect Feature selection functions (1) using the multi-collinearity matrix and recursively proceeding to a spearman threshold and (2) using Forward Stepwise Selection running on an ensemble sklearner (with options for HPO).</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://daniel-furman.github.io/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://daniel-furman.github.io/contact/</guid><description>Contact dryanfurman (at) gmail
Social Profiles LinkedIn Github PyPi Kaggle Resume Resume available upon request.</description></item><item><title>Resume</title><link>https://daniel-furman.github.io/resume/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://daniel-furman.github.io/resume/</guid><description>Resume available upon request.</description></item></channel></rss>