<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Daniel Furman</title><link>https://daniel-furman.github.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Daniel Furman</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://daniel-furman.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>BirdCLEF21 Kaggle Competition Write Up.</title><link>https://daniel-furman.github.io/posts/birdclef21-kaggle-competition-write-up/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://daniel-furman.github.io/posts/birdclef21-kaggle-competition-write-up/</guid><description>BirdCLEF21 Kaggle Competition Write Up. The BirdCLEF21 Kaggle competition task was to classify bird calls by their species (397 target classes). These bird call recognition models were aimed at streamlining and semi-automating ecosystem monitoring for bird assemblages.
TLDR
I blended several CNNs taking 7-second spectrogram representations of .ogg bird call files. I employed stripe augmentations and mixup to improve the CNNs’ generalization to out of training domains. For inference, we predict on padded 5 sec snippets and refine the result with a metadata gradient boosting classifier and postprocessing.</description></item><item><title>Numerical Math Mondays: Approximating the golden ratio.</title><link>https://daniel-furman.github.io/posts/numerical-math-mondays-approximating-the-golden-ratio/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://daniel-furman.github.io/posts/numerical-math-mondays-approximating-the-golden-ratio/</guid><description>Numerical Math Mondays: Approximating the golden ratio.
The first in hopefully what will be many Numerical Math Mondays. My goal for this series of posts is to dive back into the numerical mathematics topics I learned during my undergraduate studies. I am a huge fan of 3blue1brown, and so, I am looking to pay particular attention to the visual side of the mathematics, as well as the computational.</description></item><item><title>Solving a partnership restructuring problem with Markov processes.</title><link>https://daniel-furman.github.io/posts/solving-a-partnership-restructuring-problem-with-computational-linear-algerba/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 21:22:42 -0700</pubDate><guid>https://daniel-furman.github.io/posts/solving-a-partnership-restructuring-problem-with-computational-linear-algerba/</guid><description>Solving a partnership restructuring problem with Markov processes. Consider a partnership restructuring its assets. The N partners currently share each of the M assets at a given percentage. Our task is to re-distribute the assets such that each is under majority ownership. Critically, we need to divvy the assets without altering the overall value and debt associated with each partner. In effect, we want to split up the assets fairly.</description></item></channel></rss>